http://www.kamstrup.com/en-us/about-kamstrup/data-privacy-policy

News
Let us come to you!
Blog
English (US)
North America
English (Global)
English (US)
Toggle navigation
Language: English (US)
Data Privacy Policy
At Kamstrup, we respect data privacy and it is our top priority to protect data, prevent misuse and loss of data. We respect the trust all our stakeholders have in our ability to handle their data in a secure and trustworthy way. All data is handled in accordance to the European General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) and other applicable data protection regulations.
We value the trust you show us, when entrusting your personal information to us, and we will only use your information in relation to the presented purposes and the consent given by you. Furthermore, Kamstrup will only keep your data for the period it is legitimately reasonable to do so. Thereafter, the data collected by us or given to us by you will be deleted. This Privacy Policy will provide a thorough overview of what type of information is collected, how data is used and if shared with any third party relation.
Categories
Kamstrup processes personal data in the following categories:
when you visit our websites e.g. when surfing the websites, filling in a form etc.,
when we process data for marketing purposes, including subscription to a newsletter and responding to customer surveys via e-mail or on our website,
when you participate in an event, trade fair etc., and are in touch with Kamstrup before, during and after the event e.g. as part of queries or sales,
When you send inquiries to Kamstrup in general e.g. contacting Kamstrup by e-mail, social media or the like.
Data types
Depending on which category you belong to (see the above); different data will be collected about you. The data types for each category are listed below:
1. Website visitor
Queries sent via the website and response received by e-mail
In relation to “Search the job” under the career tab separate information is given
Login information when creating an account on My Kamstrup
2. Marketing
Name, telephone number, e-mail address, postal address, job title and area of interest
Company or organisation of employment
Information about consent granted for marketing purposes
Tracking the processing of online marketing received e.g. whether the message was opened and which links were clicked on etc.
Metering information including costs (mechanical and ultrasonic meters)
3. Events
Name, job title, e-mail address and telephone number
Area of interest
Company or organisation of employment
Participation in trade fairs and events
4. General inquiries
Name, telephone number, e-mail address, postal address, job title and area of interest
Data protocols and similar detailed product information
Purpose for collecting data
Depending on the category (see above), we collect information with the following purposes:
To improve our website enabling us to serve you and present our services in the best possible way
To follow up on queries and correspondence by e-mail, telephone and online forms
To improve our level of service and optimise our marketing initiatives
To send direct marketing via e-mail, etc. as described in the consent form
To ensure compliance with applicable legislation e.g. EU GDPR, ePrivacy Directive and the Danish Marketing Practice Act.
To be able to provide documentation of compliance with legislation
To ensure initiation and maintenance of technical and organisational security measures
To be able to process queries and complaints from people registered and others
To ensure that we can investigate any suspicion or knowledge of security breaches and report to the people registered and the authorities
To be able to deal with inspections and queries from supervisory authorities
To be able to manage disputes with people registered and third parties
To be able to perform statistical analysis
The profiling enables us to deliver punctual and relevant communication based on submitted information, visitor history, visitor behaviour on the website and tracking data form e-mails etc. The information is used for segmentation of the target group.
Source
Personal data is collected directly from you, including any queries made by you or the company you represent by telephone, e-mail, at trade fairs etc. Data is also received via the website e.g. through e-mail inserts and other tracking mechanisms.
Legal basis for collecting and processing personal data
The legal basis for the processing of data for the above purposes is as follows:
Consent for direct marketing e-mail, cf. the Danish Marketing Practice Act
Website and the use of other tracking mechanisms in e-mails, cf. ePrivacy Directive
The provision on the balancing of interests in Article 6(1)(f), as it is in Kamstrup’s legitimate interests to provide you and the company you represent a focused service and to be able to protect IT systems and data about the company
Our legal obligations as a data service provider e.g. in terms of IT security
Necessary steps taken at your request prior to entering into a potential contract
Necessary steps taken in order to provide in queries with any information requested by you
Should a dispute arise between a third party, e.g. your employer and us, the legal basis defines how we can determine, defend and plead our legal claim.
Withdrawal of consent
If the processing is based on consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent. This will not affect the processing of data handed over or done prior to the withdrawal of consent.
Storage period
We keep your personal data on file in our CRM system during the period we are in contact with you, and the company you represent. It is possible that we will keep them longer, if this is required to manage documentation, contractual performance or legal requirements.
Data concerning documentation of consent for receiving promotional material sent by e-mail (direct marketing only) is kept for three years after being sent (as per the rules on limitation of action). This is unless other data is included in the same communication that justifies a longer processing period for other purposes e.g. a legal requirement.
In conformity with legal requirements, we process this data for as long as it is necessary to manage third party interests or our interests.
Obligation to provide information
You are not obligated to give us the information we request from you. However, please be informed that if you refrain from submitting the required information, you may not be entitled to use services offered.
Your rights
You have certain rights, under the restrictions stipulated in GDPR. The rights include:
The right to access personal data
The right to edit incorrect information
The right to have information deleted
The right to restrict the processing of information
The right to data portability, and
The righto object to the processing of personal data.
You also have the right to file a complaint with a competent authority, including the Danish Data Protection Agency.
Changes
We may change our Privacy Policy over time. The updated Privacy Policy applies to your continued use of the website and our use of personal data. We kindly ask you to review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis.
Contact
If you have any questions about the processing of your personal data or the exercising of your rights, please contact us at dpo@kamstrup.com.
Kamstrup A/S, Industrivej 28, DK-8660 Skanderborg
We use cookies both to ensure our website works properly and to collect statistics about users in order for us to improve the website. You accept the use of cookies by continuing to browse the site or by closing this banner. Read more.
I understand and accept
